Henry Snopek

Frontend Developer and Software Engineer (262) 923-0261, hhsnopek@gmail.com, https://hhsnopek.com

About

I'm an experienced Frontend Developer with a well rounded background in full-stack development. I look to push the boundaries of the web, lead projects to success, and help others learn and grow. I've been working at an agency since 2015 and have been fortunate to work on an extremely wide range of projects. During this time I've gained experience in both frontend and backend technologies and experimented with the latest tooling and libraries. I've lead teams of 1-4 people, with other departments, and acted as client contact. I actively participate in open source software, whether it's helping another developer understand a project, writing documentation, or bug fixing. I'm particularly interested in Progress Web Apps, Static websites, and Electron Applications.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science, Carroll University, Waukesha, WI May 2016

<u>Skills</u>

Languages: Javascript, Golang, Bash Source Code Management: Git

Frameworks/Technologies: React, Electron & Node, GraphQL, RESTful APIs, Webpack, Parcel Bundler, Nginx,

AWS management & deployment, Docker, Headless CMS, Linux

Experience

Developer, Carrot Creative (rebranded to Virtue), Brooklyn, NYC

June 2016 - Present

- Assisted in product development of suave.com rebuild with Adobe Experience Manager
- Managed and developed frontend tooling for static sites with Roots, Spike, and React Static
- Built Single Page Applications using Create React App (pinterestsecretsanta.com)
- Lead developer and client contact for P&G Children's Safe Drinking Water rebuild of csdw.org
- Mentored coworkers on various tooling (create-react-app, spike, & react-static), react, golang APIs, and in both frontend & backend best-practices

Developer Intern, Carrot Creative, Brooklyn, NYC

June 2015 – Aug 2015

- Refactored Share Button, +3000 stars, +65 million asset requests/month (github.com/carrot/share-button)
- Proposed and rewrote Carrot internal apps using Microservices with Golang and Docker
- Led development of tumblr themes for Espolon Tequila (psstzine.tumblr.com) and Elizabeth Arden (teamtaylorswiftfragrances.tumblr.com)

Open Source Projects & Contributions

Beer O'Clock (github.com/hhsnopek/beeroclock)

Jan 2017

Proof of concept Bash service

Blog Writeup (hackernoon.com/a-web-service-written-in-pure-bash-2af847902df1)

Up (github.com/apex/up)

Nov 2017 - Present

Deploy infinitely scalable serverless apps, apis, and sites in seconds to AWS.

Code Frame (github.com/hhsnopek/code-frame)

Aug 2016 - Present

Minimal Code Frame like babel-code-frame, but smaller

Jumblr (github.com/hhsnopek/jumblr)

Oct 2014 - May 2015

Jade Tumblr Mixins

10Kft Stopwatch (github.com/carrot/10k-stopwatch)

July 2014

A chrome extension that starts/stops the time tracker that hooks into 10000ft.com

roots (roots.cx)

May 2013 - 2016

A toolbox for building simple, beautiful, and efficient products for the web.

ship (github.com/carrot/ship)

Dec 2013 - 2016

Multi-platform deployment with node.